Whoa -hoo.
Ah, so this is another trip you think
you're going on, Jim? No, it's not a
Jim, I... Oh,
she is brisk out there.
Ah, yes.
There's nothing like an adventure in the
great outdoors to give a man a... An
appetite? No, a... Hence of what life is
really all about, girl.
Survival, freedom close to nature.
Right, Daniel?
Well, I think it's safe to say you'll
survive overnight.
Did you remember to pack an extra heavy
sweater?
You don't pack to go ice fishing, woman.
You wear the clothes on your back.
Travel lightly.
Really lightly.
Oh, now you make sure you and Felix
don't catch cold.
Mother, we are men.
Yes, we like roughing it.
These would be nice.
Roughing it, indeed.
Why are you looking that way?
Which way?
Your lips are all pursed up. They're not
pursed up. They are.
You look like you're angry with the
world. I'm not angry with the world.
Oh, well, it's just me you're angry
with, then.
Yeah, but I know you love the
experience.
I really want you to do it.
You've made that perfect plan.
Well, then, right.
You spend far too much time in that
workshop of yours, and you get out more.
This is the perfect opportunity to spend
some time with Alex.
I think you two could become friends.
Good friends.
You're part of my family now, Jasper. I
want you to like them.
Like them?
Well, it's important to me.
Don't see how going ice fishing with
Alex is going to cement my relationship
with your family.
Well, I can't hurry.
Good night.
Eddie and Olivia will be here any
minute. They're nowhere near ready.
Eddie and Olivia thought you were going
with Abigail.
Oh, well, I was, but you know how Olivia
loves a noxian, and I couldn't very
well ask her, not Eddie. And then I
thought, well, why not make an event of
and we'll all say to the White Sands for
tea afterwards.
Won't that be fun, just the four of us?
Couldn't handle a day alone with
Abigail.
Oh, Alec, it's not that at all.
She can be a little, you know... Safety
in numbers?
Yes.
Hello,
Uncle Jasper.
Hello, sir.
Jasper, stop looking as though you're
going to the gallows.
Whatever you say, Olivia.
See about that.
Oh, Scotty. Oh, well, this entire event
goes against my better judgment. You
know that.
Abigail and Janet spending the day
together.
Impossible. They're like oil and water,
those two. Don't mix.
Bound to end in disaster.
Remember, we have a wager, Olivia.
Oh, I remember. I still think they'll
get along just fine.
and it will be off.
Are you ready to brave the elements,
man?
What?
I'm going to take care of you today,
aren't I, Daniel?
Don't scare him, Sarah.
Notice that you don't know anything
about babies.
I know just as much as you do.
You don't know more than me about
anything.
Ha! Bet?
Any time.
Fine. Shake.
So go ahead. Tell me something I don't
know.
There, you see?
I win.
You're really such a toad.
I'll think of something.
Ha!
I'm finally ready. We don't want to be
late for the auction.
Abigail's here.
Oh, this dog! Oh, my! Get this dog down!
Abigail, how are you? Good to see you,
Janet.
Come on, Robert.
Lucky, aren't you getting big?
Oh, my little man is growing.
Aren't you, Robert?
And how is Daniel?
Is he talking yet?
Oh, no, he's only nine months, but he's
crawling to beat the bed. Isn't that
funny? Robert spoke his first words at
nine months.
One minute. Oh,
Abigail, dear, you think you were
staying for a month.
There are more things out in the buggy.
Could you get them for me, please? Oh,
yes, Abigail.
Whatever you say.
Ever since Digger arrived, we never have
to wash the floor.
That's disgusting, Janet.
Ralph!
Don't go near that dog. He'll bite you.
He doesn't bite. Oh, he won't bite.
Digger's never bitten anyone.
Oh.
So that's where Mother's bowl platter
went.
Felicity, don't give Robert his
applesauce until he's had his beef stew,
corn, and his peas.
Oh, Abigail, you didn't have to bring
your own applesauce. I've got some of my
own right here. Oh, Janet, you put far
too much sugar in yours.
Janet!
Well,
let's just forget we're mothers for a
day and go and have some fun.
Oh, dear.
Now, Robert, you give mother a kiss.
Felicity, it'll ruin his appetite.
Well, it's totally ruining mine. Come
on.
Come along, Abigail.
Join me if you like.
I already got a nice warm hut on the
ice.
I was catching on a large catch this
winter, but the fish seem to be staying
away in droves.
Oh, thank you, Gus. We will.
Now, uh, speaking of staying away... We
don't see enough of you.
We'd better go and find more offers.
Well, I just might take you up on that.
That old lighthouse gets a bit lonely in
the winter.
I don't want to say hello or goodbye to
you. I've had enough of that kind of
independence.
I'm glad my bachelor days are over.
I'm with you there, Jasper.
Well, I must admit, sometimes I get
thinking about settling down, getting me
farm, maybe even a wife.
A wife?
How old was Method King when you
first...
You know, started courting her. Oh, I
don't remember. Fifteen.
Fifteen?
How about 50's 15?
Well, how did you know she was 15?
It was that social.
Emmett Frazier's. Yeah, so?
So, she told her father she was going
with me.
With you? Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Well, he approved of me.
Wasn't so sure of you.
He ran with a rambunctious crowd.
Father? Oh, yeah, we were quite a wild
bunch there. Ed Lawson, Bert Potts, and
Amos Bryce.
So, you don't think 15 is too young for
a girl to go to parking? Well, I mean,
that depends on the girl.
You know, I mean, Janet now, she was
mature when 15.
about that, Hedy, but having young
children is rather like that.
Yes. Oh, nonsense.
You simply have to learn to let them go.
Oh, really? Well, Janet and I happen to
feel that young children need their
mother. Janet, there are so many
dressers around. Did you look for one
boys? Oh, yes, Abigail. Let's go have a
closer look.
Oh, look,
Hedy, commemorative stone.
Oh, I only like the Queen Victoria ones.
Everything fine between you and Jasper,
is it?
Of course. Why do you ask?
Oh, I don't know.
I thought I sensed a little strain there
in paradise.
You know, Lydia, I've always found it
best to try to let the lives of those we
love run their own course, not to
control anything.
Do you really expect me to take that
seriously, coming from you?
No, I think you're absolutely right,
Abigail. It's too high, but this one is
splendid. Oh, it's beautiful.
Ooh.
Veneer. Can't imagine anyone paying good
money for junk like this.
Oh, really?
Well, it's got lots of drawer space.
Not that Felix puts his clothes away
anyway, but... You have to teach them
young, Janet.
Oh? My Robert? He already knows to put
his things in the proper place.
Isn't he a mar...
Lucky. It broke.
Mother's favorite.
He's going to be very angry.
You're supposed to be looking after him,
Sarah. I was watching Daniel.
Well, I can't do everything.
I'm making the supper.
Where's he up to now?
You know what's up, Felix?
What? Last time.
Jasper and I were out here. We were your
age.
Nice fishing.
Twelve years old.
A bunch of us played hockey from school
and... Now, was that Bert
Potts who could only skate backwards?
Don't think so.
No, it was you.
It was you. Do you remember? You were
skating backwards. Full speed. Went
into the open water.
Pulled me out.
Reckon you saved my life on that one.
I don't know, but you sure looked a
sight.
Clothes all frozen in your body.
Poor guy. He was freezing to death, and
he looks so darn funny, you know?
I suppose so.
I always thought I owed you one on that
one.
I don't think we ever went ice fishing
again after that.
I guess we went our separate ways.
People change.
You got one!
Whoa!
And there she goes. It must be a fish.
Pull her up there, boy.
Ladies and gentlemen, how much am I bid?
Bid, Hattie, bid.
Fifty cents.
Fifty cents. Anybody fifty -five?
Oh, Hattie, don't get so tight.
Go higher.
Sold to Hattie King, who has
successfully outbid herself.
Oh,
Hattie. Sorry, but it's an excellent
price.
Abigail, what number is the dresser? 36.
Oh, good.
It's up soon, then.
This beautiful piece of work has been
signed by the artist himself.
The silver comes from Mexico. Janet. And
there isn't any here.
Janet, where are you going?
Ladies and gentlemen, one of my bids for
this fine music box, which has been in
the same family for generations.
Generations, my auntie. Things brand
new.
Made of genuine silver.
Tin. One of my bids.
Damn, I bid a dollar and a half.
Anybody bid me a dollar fifty?
One dollar.
One dollar bid. Anybody bid him a two?
A dollar fifty.
I have a dollar fifty. Anybody two? What
about the dresser? I bid a dollar
fifty. Now, anybody want him a two?
Two dollars.
Two dollars. Two fifty.
Two fifty. Thank you, ma 'am. It is a
piece of rubbish.
If she won't fit, I can imagine why.
Two. Fifty bid anybody three.
Three. Fifty. Three.
Fifty bid anybody four.
Three. Fifty bid anybody buy them at
four.
Going once. Going twice.
Five dollars.
Sold to the lady with the fur hat.
Moving along, ladies and gentlemen. Item
number 32 in your catalog. Fuzzy brain.
Women? And, um, men?
What about them?
Well, you know, women and men together.
Well?
What? What do you know about them?
really something you can talk about.
You have to sort of go through it.
Then you'll know.
But how do I know that I've gone through
it when I don't even know what it is?
You'll know.
Boy, it's getting cold out here.
Lucky, if you don't come back here, I'm
going to make you wear this. Lucky.
This is impossible.
You just don't know how to handle him,
Sarah.
Lucky, come back here and finish this
stew.
That's never going to work. No!
You see?
Lucky!
Left, right, left, right, left, right.
Company up on the chair.
Company, eat.
You see? All it takes is a little
psychology.
Lucky Diggle will get it.
You must have seen that man wink at the
auctioneer, the two -wheeling coots,
clearly. But he set out to get a draft.
He ended up with this music box.
And I end up paying for it to boot.
Well, it's just a little short, I'll
tell you that.
That's what you said the last time,
dear.
Oh, ladies.
I have a very special table for you.
Would you please follow me?
Looks like the fish are back.
Mr. Dale did it.
like it here, Father.
Good. It's nice to get away, huh?
Yeah.
A day like this, I feel I could ask you
anything.
And you'd be able to answer it, man to
man.
Well, I'm flattered.
I'd certainly try.
You would?
Of course.
If you've got any questions for me, you
go right ahead.
Well, there's one thing that's been
bothering me.
What's that?
What do men and women do?
Well,
you know, when they're married.
You cut yourself!
You're bleeding.
Here. It's all right. Don't worry.
So?
So? I caught you, remember?
Oh, yes, yes. Well, men and women.
Well, um, you know how, uh, how bees are
attracted to flowers.
Well, uh, the bee buzzes around and, um,
you know, it's buzzing
and buzzing and... I know that part.
Well... What part don't you know about?
That's just it. I don't know the part I
don't know. I just know that there's got
to be a part that I don't know about,
and that's the part that I've got to
Yeah.
Um... Have you asked your mother about
this?
Asper? Yeah.
Mind if I ask her something?
Sure. Don't know.
But I'll be able to do nothing.
Sure.
When did you know you were in love with
Meth Kang?
I mean, Olivia.
Well, I hardly... Gosh.
I didn't dare think about it for quite
some time, but I'd say...
How do you know?
Well, you just do.
I mean, I just did.
I felt...
Sort of thick.
Right here.
Never felt that way before.
Sort of... Sort of lurching.
Yeah, I know that feeling.
Sort of like right here. Yeah, yeah.
Kind of like being seasick. Yeah,
be it.
And the gut. Yeah, and the gut.
Every time I see Olivia... That's both
of you.
I know.
I still do.
But...
A lot more to being in love than feeling
sick.
Oh, for sure.
Felicity?
Huh? I don't know.
She's something.
She sure is.
Actually, she reminds me of someone.
Howdy.
McKay?
Lovely. Abigail, isn't this the exact
china pattern that you have at home?
Oh, yes.
Yes.
And it's the one thing that Mother gave
me that I cherish the most.
It's the one thing Mother promised me as
a wedding present.
No, she didn't, Janet.
Yes, it was lovely. So glad you talked
me into coming, Olivia.
I was
only
joking, Felicity. Let me go. Let me go.
Let me go. There.
That should do it.
Now we can do our work and not have to
worry about where that little monster
Father always said that was the best
part.
Oh, well, you eat it then.
Gosh, it's good to get together like
this, eh? We used to pal around a lot,
didn't we? I'll never forget the time
you ran Hattie's bloomers up the
at school.
And Hattie's underwear?
It can't be serious.
And you, you were the one who hit the
hornet's nest in the back of Abigail
Ward's desk.
when we locked Ed Lawson in the church
basement with a skunk.
That was me I locked in the church
Oh, that's right, he was.
Your parents wouldn't let you in the
house for about a week. I had to sleep
GED barn.
Those were the days, huh?
Remember when we used to take those
Arctic swims?
Arctic swim?
Jump into fishing hole.
You're joking, right?
Come on.
Let's do it.
What? Come on. We're not old men yet.
You went there.
Oh, really? Right.
We'll see about that.
You're on.
Fate is where you got that idea, Janet,
dear.
But you're welcome to it.
Thank you. Heaven knows how many other
things you've spirited away.
Spirited away?
Now, what do you mean? I have never held
myself to anything that was rightfully
yours. Janet, don't pretend that spoke
platter of yours didn't come directly
from my dining room cabinet.
I borrowed it. Well, clearly you had no
need of it.
Oh, my goodness, one little piece of
china.
If you wanted it back so badly, all you
had to do was ask for it.
and let me down off this thing.
I'd rather walk, thank you, than listen
to another word of this.
Oh, but, but, Hedy, the girls are
preparing supper for us. You can send
back immediately, and the next time you
two plan a lovely afternoon together,
you can count me out.
Now, don't say something you'll regret
later. Oh, now, quiet it, Libby, and get
down. Come on.
Oh, Hoby. My only regret will be if I
don't say something.
You two can put your foot around each
other for the rest of your natural -born
days, for all I care, but it makes me
sick. to listen to it.
Well, just drop this ridiculous charade.
Say whatever it is you really want to
say to each other and be done with it.
Oh, you words are all the same.
You do well to grow up, the both of you.
Oh, well, if that's the way you feel,
Harry King, fine.
meant for me to do the craziest things,
even when I knew better.
I'm a bloody fool. That's what I am.
Jasper, I don't know how I can... You
know, I... If you hadn't been here, I
might have drowned.
There's a big blizzard on the way.
Good.
Well, Hedy certainly cut off her nose to
spite her face. She's going to miss a
darn good dinner. And all because you
and I had a little disagreement.
Oh, and thank you for picking up the
bill for tea. I'll reimburse you as soon
we get home.
What are sisters for?
Just a little draining to be with
someone who so obviously refuses to act
age. I think you're carrying on like
that at that auction and then disgracing
all in public.
Advocate, I didn't. You acted like a
witness schoolgirl over that cheap, ugly
music box. And then humiliating me with
that waiter at the White Sands Hotel.
Oh, how foolish of me. I haven't got a
penny in my purse.
Advocate, I didn't.
Fathering must be turning over his grave
in embarrassment.
Yes, Mr.
King. Um, I've been, um, trying to get
some, um, information.
Good, good.
Information's always useful.
That's good to hear from you, knowing
that, um, you're a married man and all.
Um, and that you know, you know all
about life.
Life?
Life? Yeah.
Oh, I see.
Well,
what did your father tell you about?
Nothing. Something stupid about bees
buzzing.
Well, I've always been one to think that
you never find out about anything until
you ask the right questions. So you're
right to ask.
Actually, it's all quite scientific in
one way.
No, no, no.
The whole question comes down to true,
strong, basic
human emotion.
Are we talking about the same thing?
Yeah, I think we are.
And
knowledge
is never a...
Maybe we should bring the little culprit
inside.
They'll be back any minute, and I'd hate
for Aunt Abigail to see her beloved
little Robert tied to a clothesline.
I suppose you're right.
Oh, no.
Sarah, he's gone!
Will Abigail say something? I'm being so
childish.
It's just like when we were children.
Every time you were losing an argument,
you just...
Start from the beginning.
Well?
Lucky!
Lucky, where are you?
Lucky?
Don't worry, Sarah, we'll find him.
I know these words like the back of my
hand.
Lucky!
Why have we passed the three stump three
times?
You know, Janet has no sense of
direction, whatever.
They'll probably find themselves
hopelessly lost.
Precisely. Right as rain.
And the girls?
Oh, they're probably home by now, too.
Come on, now. Let's head in that
direction. Come on. Oh, no, no, no, no,
Hedy. I think it's this way.
Oh, no, no, Janet.
This is the way.
Then go.
I don't want to stay here with the
babies. I know the woods are
anyone can find them, I can.
I'll come with you.
Stanley, you stay here.
I know.
There you go, Gus.
So, how was the auction?
Oh, well... I think it was very
successful.
That was the song you used to sing to me
when we were recording.
I promise I'm never going to try to talk
you into anything that you don't want
to do. Oh, no, no, no. You're absolutely
right, Lemya.
I'm glad you made me go.
But you promised me one thing.
You'd never make me eat fish fried in
lard.
Alec King, did you make Jasper eat fish
fried in lard?
It's a family tradition.
One we could do without.
What ever happened to that King family
spirit?
Alec, remember that time you and Father
caught all those fish?
And he asked me how many were in the
sack, and I said 24, thinking he meant
fillets. Right, but he meant fish, and
he kept asking and asking, and you kept
saying 24, 24.
I thought he'd never speak to me again.
He was purple with frustration.
I win again, Felix.
Um, Sarah?
You know the bet we talked about?
Yeah?
Might have something you don't know.
What?
Felix, I knew that.
I'd like to make a toast.
Seeing as I'm so good at them.
To friends.
Yeah, yeah.
And relations.
And relations. Yes, indeed.